Puspha Raj Pandeya

Worked as a machine learning engineer for the past 2 years and have gained a lot of experience in the field. I have also developed a strong learning attitude which helps me keep up with the latest trends in the industry.

Koteshwor, Kathmandu 9865376688 puspharajpandey@gmail.com

Github

<u>LinkedIn</u>

EXPERIENCE

Eydean Inc., Naya Bazaar — Machine Learning Engineer

May 2022- PRESENT

- Build a data pipeline with ELK stack and GraphQL for creating a sales analysis dashboard.
- Performed ETL on different databases to create data warehouses for easy data analysis and visualizations.
- Worked on creating a logistic management system for fastest delivery of products with efficient use of resources.
- Created content based recommendation system and sales forecasting models.
- Assisted Devops team by creating Docker and Nginx configurations.
- Worked on API creation of one project using Flask.
- Data migration from SQL to NoSQL.

Eydean Inc., Lazimpat — *Software Developer*

November 2021 - April 2022

- Created data visualization dashboard using Metabase.
- Created a functional map having navigation using Leaflet js, osmnx, networkx and folium.
- Worked as backend developer on some projects using Python.
- Performed data analysis of many ERP clients.

Technocolabs Softwares, Indore — *Machine Learning Intern*

October 2021 - November 2021

- Worked on a project called 'Using NLP Techniques to Predict Song Skips on Spotify based on Acoustic-Data'.
- Lead a team of 6 people on this project.
- Created a sequential model for skip prediction using LSTM and Light GBT algorithms.

SKILLS

Programming: Python, Flask, FastAPI, Django

Database: MySQL, Postgresql, MongoDB

Data Science: Machine Learning Algorithms and Libraries, NLP and Computer Vision

Data Engineering: ETL using python and SQL, ELK stack (Elastic search, logstash, kibana)

Server Side: Docker, Nginx

Version Control: Git

EDUCATION

NCIT, Kathmandu— Computer *Engineering*

September 2017 - September 2021

PROJECTS

Sentiment Analysis for Business Reviews

Brain Tumor Detection

Heart Disease Detection

LANGUAGES

Nepali, English, Hindi